<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Googleappengine | This is One of the Solutions]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.prabeeshk.com/blog/categories/googleappengine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.prabeeshk.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-15T22:46:34+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://blog.prabeeshk.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prabeesh K]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paint App Using JavaScript and Canvas]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.prabeeshk.com/blog/2013/03/30/paint-app-using-javascript-and-canvas/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T12:44:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.prabeeshk.com/blog/2013/03/30/paint-app-using-javascript-and-canvas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An application to draw simple drawings using lines, rectangles and circles in different colours.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/paint.png" width="850" height="350" title="&lsquo;image&rsquo; &lsquo;images&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The application is developed using JavaScript and HTML5. The canvas feature in HTML5 is used for providing a drawable region. The JavaScript is used to handle drawing functions in these region. The select button to select the different tools to draw. The colour picker is made using the button option. The script basically listen three mouse events mousedown, mousemove and mouseup. This application implemented using two different frameworks Google App Engine and Flask.</p>

<h3>Application with saving facility</h3>

<p>This is done by saving values about each object needed to regenerate the same drawing. When we click the save button the data is transferred to the server as a json string where it is stored along with a name provided by the user. Simply regenerate the drawing using the data received from the server.</p>

<p>In Google App Engine Google data storage is used for data storage. But in Flask sqlite3 is used for data storage.</p>

<p>Source code: <a href="https://github.com/prabeesh/Paintapp-Javascript-Canvas-GAE">App with GAE</a> and <a href="https://github.com/prabeesh/Paintapp-Javascript-Canvas-Flask">App with Flask</a></p>

<p>The app is deployed in appspot.com, You can find the application <a href="http://prabs-paint.appspot.com/">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
